<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Drama, Film & Theatre Portfolio]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website</link><image><url>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Drama, Film &amp; Theatre Portfolio</title><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:42:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:41:57 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[ACT 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our first Applied Creative Task (ACT) was an Ensemble1 Driven Piece of Theatre, it took place between <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="October 2025" data-href="October 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/october-2025/october-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">October</a> 16th and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="November 2025" data-href="November 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/november-2025/november-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">November</a> 17th when we performed it for our class. We were split into groups of 5-6 people, and with about 24ish students gave us 4 groups. My group was designated Group 1 and it consisted of:
Conor Maguire
Sholadh Garland
Seán Kavanagh
Katelynn Tyrell Clinton
Alex Gahan
Freya Darcy
<br>We started by selecting our roles within the group, with our Actors<a data-footref="2" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fn-1-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[1]</a>, Director<a data-footref="3" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fn-2-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[2]</a>, Stage &amp; Set Designer<a data-footref="4" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fn-3-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[3]</a> and Script Writer<a data-footref="5" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fn-4-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[4]</a>. Due to the fact that we only had 6 people, many people were required to take on multiple roles.<br>As a prompt to derive inspiration from for our performance, we were given the scene <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qt5LLLU_qew" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qt5LLLU_qew" target="_self">"What About My Life"</a> from the drama Fences. In said scene we see two characters a husband and wife, the husband complains about being stuck in the same spot for the past few years, the wife gives out to him for this saying that she's been stuck right there with him, and how she's sacrificed so much of her hopes, wants and dreams to be with him. The scene is extremely emotionally charged with both verbal and physical conflict. This emotionality was our inspiration for our drama, and so, we set out to create our own drama piece with heavy emotions and some conflict.
After bouncing ideas around and coming up with different bits, we started with a murder scene for that emotional charge and further developed that into a noir murder mystery. (see summary for more). This throwing of ideas continued for about a class period, it mainly consisted of someone saying "What if we do x" or "Hey wouldn't it be cool if we did y", followed by someone else going sure why not. Eventually we got to the point where we had a whole host of characters, twists and scenes, something that resembled a story. I then wrote a draft of a few scenes and we went through the scenes, changing what didn't flow right, with a bit of improvisation to make dialogue that we all liked.
This is also when we came up with a bunch of different accents and some rough ideas for costumes. We didn't have a specific costume designer for the characters, instead giving everyone the opportunity to create there own costumes that they thought would best suit their character, which I think worked well.
About halfway through the process of developing our piece, every group was advised to stick to one set because the assembling and disassembling of sets would eat into our already limited time. And as such we cut down from 5 or so sets to 3 sets, which was still more than every other group but did require us to rework and remove some scenes. I think this was a good choice because those scenes that were removed weren't essential and were realistically more effort than they were worth.Our rehearsals started as just simple reading and learning of lines whilst sitting around a table until we had sets designed, during this time we did checks to see if it was too long or too short, allotting time for actions and stage assembly. Once the stages were designed by Alex Gahan who was our Stage Designer, we then used to build our sets and rehearsed the scenes with full acting and stage set up. Due to the aforementioned cutting of scenes, we had a few stages that were designed which were binned, and while the wasted effort was a pain, it was for the best that we didn't waste the little time we had. Throughout the rehearsals we all did our best to use accents and such, for two purposes:
To practice our skills in varying the usage of our voices, this will stand to benefit us later if asked to change voices.
This also allowed us find the exact right voice for our characters.
We continued rehearsing the entire drama with full set for a while, once we only had a few more rehearsals till our performance, we moved to using our full costumes and props. For props we had a few fake guns which people had, as well as a knife that I made out of cardstock. We tried to buy as little as we needed to, to make our costumes instead opting for stuff we had at home or if we really needed to, we bought from charity stores.
Our sets were as follows:
<br>: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Stage1.jpg" data-href="Stage1.jpg" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Alleyway</a>
<br>: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Stage2.jpg" data-href="Stage2.jpg" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage2.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Police Interrogation/Question Room</a>
<br>: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Stage3.jpg" data-href="Stage3.jpg" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage3.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Evidence Office</a>
The set designs can be viewed via clicking on the links above
The performance of our drama was on Monday the 17th of November 2025. It was initially intended to be on Friday the 14th, however due to problems with props and costumes going missing we had to postpone it. While somewhat inconvenient that it had to be delayed, it was also very useful to fully fully get our lines right and refined.Our first scene opens with a lone character in an alleyway, Shanice Durkin calls out to a man named Tommy but he's nowhere to be found, instead a mysterious figure enters the alleyway and stabs Shanice in the back. After the mysterious figure flees the scene of the crime, Margaret Durkin enters the alleyway, not realising that her granddaughter has just been murdered in cold blood. She realises what has happened and breaks down in tears.
In our next scene, Bob Brien and Felicia Rider enter the alleyway to the scene of the crime, the examine the body and collect evidence for later inspection.
Our third scene features an interrogation room, with both detectives and Margaret Durkin, she tells them what happens and how Shanice was looking for someone called Tommy, she pleads with them to find who killed her granddaughter.
Continuing with the interrogation room, the elusive Tommy is being questioned, he says how he doesn't know anyone named Shanice but upon being threatened with jail time for lying, he tells the detectives how he was going to meet her but was with another customer at the time. He's questioned as to what he's selling and he asks for his lawyer. His lawyer Fred Squirkgel enters the interrogation room, setting his briefcase on the table, he informs the detectives of Tommy's dog walking business and how he was meeting a customer to walk their dog. Bob opens Tommy's bag and finds a small bag of drugs, he's taken away and the scene ends.
Scene 5, begins in a separate office, Bob sits at a table, illuminated only by a lamp. The table he sits is covered with pieces of evidence, documents, a lone red star that was collected from the crime scene and a bottle of beer. Bob muses about the case and possibilities, before coming to the realisation that the killer is Fred, he bolts up shouting the name and the lights cut to black.
The final scene opens to the detectives re-entering the alleyway and hiding, the two of them bicker with Felicia trying to convince Bob that Fred isn't the killer. Margaret Durkin enters the alleyway with Fred sneaking just behind her. Before Fred can stab Margaret, Bob points his gun at him telling him to freeze. Bob and Fred squabble back and forth which ends with Felicia betraying and shooting Bob. Fred finishes off Margaret and our drama comes to a close.Overall I think we were very successful in carrying out our first ACT, together as a group and using our given prompt, we created a drama piece that we're proud of (At least I am). We effectively made use of stage and costume design to create our atmosphere, tone and gestures to convey character emotions (For example, Alex used stuttering and scratching to show Tommy's nervousness).
I really enjoyed working on this project as a whole but specifically I enjoyed writing the script for the drama. I found it quite fun to write in a script format as it came surprisingly naturally to me, despite never writing in the style before. In addition to enjoying scriptwriting, I also loved the acting portion, I've always loved to put on little voices or accents, practicing different stances or facial expressions to show different subtexts like the tiny difference between a genuine kind smile or a fake deceptive one. In conclusion I thoroughly enjoyed this ACT and I'm looking forward to the next one as well as any other practical projects that we get to carry out.
1: <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Terminology > Actor" data-href="Terminology#Actor" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/terminology.html#Actor" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Actors</a><a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fnref-1-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">↩︎</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Terminology > Director" data-href="Terminology#Director" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/terminology.html#Director" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Director</a><a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fnref-2-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">↩︎</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Terminology > Stage &amp; Set Designer" data-href="Terminology#Stage &amp; Set Designer" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/terminology.html#Stage &amp; Set Designer" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Stage &amp; Set Designer</a><a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fnref-3-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">↩︎</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Terminology > Scriptwriter" data-href="Terminology#Scriptwriter" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/terminology.html#Scriptwriter" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Script Writer</a><a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fnref-4-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">↩︎</a>
]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/act-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ACTs/ACT 1/ACT 1.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:36:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Terminology]]></title><description><![CDATA[This page will contain a number of terms that some people may not know that appear throughout my digital portfolio.
An Actor is a person that acts in a drama, film or theatre piece. Chekov's Gun is a plot device that once introduced, must have significance later on in the story. It comes from the Russian playwright Anton Chekov who gave the advice about including such plot devices, with the famous line, "One must never place a loaded rifle on the stage if it isn't going to go off." This is where the "Gun" part of Chekov's Gun comes from. The Director is the person responsible to bringing the show piece to life, they have a script, an array of actors and then must use said actors to create a story with the script. Ensemble is where there are many characters, an ensemble driven piece of theatre is a piece of theatre that is made by a group rather than a single playwright. A Playwright is a person who creates plays or pieces of drama. They often have an overlap with scriptwriters as they both write scripts. The Scriptwriter is one of the most important roles in the creation of any piece of media, they are responsible for creating the script and thus the story. The Stage &amp; Set Designer is responsible for creating the sets for pieces of drama, theatre or films. A Tableaux Vivant, also known as a still scene or a living picture, is a method of telling a story with no moving parts, all of the actors are perfectly stationary.
]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/terminology.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terminology.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:30:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[October 2025]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website?query=tag:Month" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Month">#Month</a>This is the file in which all the events of October will be detailed, any of the dates that are highlighted and/or underlined can be clicked to go the file associated with that day.]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/october-2025/october-2025.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/October 2025/October 2025.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:23:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Etherville]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Synopsis</span>" data-href="#<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Synopsis</span>" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Synopsis</span>" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Synopsis</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Our Work</span>" data-href="#<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Our Work</span>" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Our Work</span>" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Our Work</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Reflection</span>" data-href="#<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Reflection</span>" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#<span style=&quot;color rgb(0, 176, 240)&quot;>Reflection</span>" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Reflection</a>
Etherville by Eamonn Colfer is a short drama that we have studied. It details the story of the main character Elliot Dunne, a car accident victim who's quite severely disabled, barely able to do much with his legs and being confined to a wheelchair. He lives in an assisted living community for disabled people. A nurse and friend of his, Gail Nolan visits him to check up and make sure he's following his recovery plan.The titular place, Etherville, is a digital place in the virtual world, it's an open source project meaning that anyone can add to it and design things for it, allowing it to flourish and for individuals to escape from the harsh reality that many live in. One of these people that use it to escape from their own harsh reality is Elliot, allowing him to escape his disabilities and live freely in a world where he can walk around in once more. In the first scene where we see him using the headset, we see him and Sophie dancing gracefully to Tchaikovsky's Waltz of The Flowers. After they finish dancing ****We did a number of things based on the play including:
<br>A Tableux Vivant<a data-footref="1" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fn-1-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[1]</a>,
A 1 Minute Performance
<br>We were put into groups of three on the 26th of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="September 2025" data-href="September 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/september-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">September</a>, my group consisted of:
Myself
Alex O'Brien
Oliver Fagan<br>
Alex had really wanted to be the director for the group but because there was no two male characters in a scene she couldn't, so Oliver volunteered himself, I had no particular interest in being the director anyways so that's what we went with. Alex and I were both actors for our work and Oliver was the director. On the 2nd of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="October 2025" data-href="October 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/october-2025/october-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">October</a> we performed our pieces, starting with the Tableaux and then the 1 Minute Performance.
<br>The Tableux Vivant<a data-footref="1" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fn-1-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[1-1]</a> that we chose to do was one of the still shots from the opening scenes, specifically the one where Gail is looking for Elliot's emergency alert button and Elliot is just looking defeatedThe scene that we elected to do for our one minute performance was the ending scene of the drama, where Elliot is walking using crutches and has gained a happier stance in stark contrast to the beginning of the play.
For the performance we used a number of props to help bring the story to life, which were a set of crutches, a music box and some tables and a chair to build the set.
When deciding the section of the play we wanted to do, we all flicked through the scripts we were given and individually chose a scene, we then took the three scenes we'd chosen and then decided which of them to do. Me and Oliver had chosen the same scene, so we ended up going with that one.I think it was pretty easy to work in a group, at the beginning some people were a little reserved but after the first class and we'd all gotten into it, we worked well together and had fun. It was also nice to work in a smaller group rather than a massive one because it meant that individual opinions were heard and not ignored. My role as Elliot, was comprised of a lot of use of non-verbal communication as Elliot doesn't have many lines in the play apart from his monologue with Sophie. Personally I enjoyed my role because a lot of the expression and acting had to be non-verbal. For the next creative task, I think I could work a bit on rehearsing some actions and things to do while idle, such as when Gail is talking, I also could do a bit with my way of talking as I mostly stuck to my usual tone rather than something different to really embrace his character. I think that we had a pretty good performance overall and I enjoyed working with my team on this. <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Terminology > Tableaux Vivant" data-href="Terminology#Tableaux Vivant" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/terminology.html#Tableaux_Vivant_0" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tableux Vivant</a><a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fnref-1-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">↩︎</a><a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fnref-1-1-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">↩︎</a>
]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/october-2025/etherville.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/October 2025/Etherville.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:15:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stage3]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage3.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ACTs/ACT 1/Stage3.jpg</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:50:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website" length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stage2]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage2.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ACTs/ACT 1/Stage2.jpg</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:50:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website" length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stage1]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage1.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/stage1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ACTs/ACT 1/Stage1.jpg</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:49:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website" length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Home]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello, welcome to the digital part of my Drama, Film &amp; Theatre PortfolioWithin this site is my journey through this subject, in website form because I didn't like how inexpressive Google Docs or Microsoft Word was, I wanted to show my passion and love for creativity so I created this website, allowing me much more freedom.To explore the portfolio there is two options, you either
Click from link to link to traverse through the pages, starting on the <a data-href="Calendar" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/calendar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Calendar</a> page.
OR
<br>Use the file explorer feature on the left hand side of the screen to see each individual page, though I'd recommend using the <a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website?query=tag:Month" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Month">#Month</a> pages to see the entries in an organised form.
<br>Throughout my portfolio, you'll find many terms highlighted in Red, these terms will have a footnote that can be clicked on which will bring you to the <a data-href="Terminology" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/terminology.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Terminology</a> where you can find their definition.P.S. Please ignore the sync and index files, I don't know why they're there, I deleted them but they won't go away.]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/home.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Home.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:26:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[README]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello welcome to the Drama, Film and Theatre portfolio of Conor Maguire. I'm studying the subject in GCS from 2025 to 2027.]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/readme.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">README.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:26:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Calendar]]></title><description><![CDATA[Within this file will be all of the months that I have spent studying the subject of Drama, Film and Theatre.It is not recommended to use the file explorer function at the side for viewing the days of each month, I'd instead recommend the visual calendar that is shown in each
<a data-href="September 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/september-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">September 2025</a>
<br><a data-href="October 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/october-2025/october-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">October 2025</a>
<br><a data-href="November 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/november-2025/november-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">November 2025</a>
]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/calendar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/Calendar.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:26:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[November 2025]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website?query=tag:Month" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Month">#Month</a> This is the file in which all the events of October will be detailed, any of the dates that are highlighted and/or underlined can be clicked to go the file associated with that day.]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/november-2025/november-2025.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/November 2025/November 2025.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:08:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[ACT 1 Script]]></title><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/act-1/act-1-script.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ACTs/ACT 1/ACT 1 Script.pdf</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:07:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[ACTs]]></title><description><![CDATA[ACTs or Applied Creative Tasks are a series of tasks that we have to complete over the course of our Leaving Cert in this subject. There is a total of 3 ACTs, all having there own goal to complete: ACT 1: Ensemble Driven Piece of Theatre
ACT 2: Short Film
ACT 3: Theatre Piece or Short Film
The ACTs are group projects in which we must work together to produce a performance piece and record it. The Theatre Pieces must be performed to an audience and recorded. Likewise the Short Films are shown to an audience.]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/acts/acts.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ACTs/ACTs.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:58:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Shadow of a Gunman (Initial Viewing)]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<a data-href="#Synopsis" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#Synopsis_0" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Synopsis</a>
<br><a data-href="#My Thoughts" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#My_Thoughts_0" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">My Thoughts</a>
<br>The Shadow of a Gunman by Sean O'Casey is a drama set during the Irish War of Independence, we follow Donal Davoren, he's a poet but everyone that knows him seems to think he's an IRA "Gunman", but he is not. He stays with Séamus Shields in a room in tenement housing, in the same building as several other characters that appear within the play. One of said characters, Mr Maguire, leaves a bag in the room, at the start of the play, like a Chekov's Gun<a data-footref="1" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fn-1-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[1]</a> I suppose, but instead of a gun that has to be fired by the third act, it's a bag that has to be opened by the end.
When Donal sees that everyone actually thinks he's a "Gunman" he plays into it, enjoying the attention and the air of mystery that it lends him, he calls himself "The Shadow of a Gunman" in a serious voice when he's alone in a scene. Another character, Minnie Powell, is the love interest of Donal, and falls in love with Donal, partially over him being a "Gunman" despite him not being one.
Eventually this act of being a "Gunman" comes back to bite him for two reasons, a tenant from a neighbouring tenement, James Gallogher, comes to him with Julia Henderson asking for the IRA's help, and he gives Donal a letter. Another tenant of the tenement is Tommy Owens, a character that had showed up praising Donal and his involvement with the IRA. He sings out the window about the IRA and the "RA" which probably had some weight in the "Black and Tans" conducting a search of the tenement housing.
And this is where our little Chekov's Bag comes to fruition, Donal and Séamus, check around the room to see if there's anything incriminating, the pair check the bag and realise it's full of bombs, Minnie takes them and hides them in her room because they won't search her room. Donal also remembers the letter which he frantically searches so he can burn it and get rid of it. Eventually the "Black and Tans" arrive and search the place, making a mess. After searching the building they arrest Minnie and take her away, but their wagon is ambushed by the IRA and she's shot.Personally I really enjoyed the drama, it's very entertaining and surprisingly tense, a lot of the humour still lands despite it being written a century ago. I really liked the use of lighting with the spotlights which were used sparingly, but when they were used they were very impactful, as well as with the Sun and Moon as physical objects that could be seen on the stage, it really helped with the immersion. The set design overall was fantastic, it looked lived in and real, rather than some artificial location, which is only made possible because of the singular location that is used throughout the drama. I also loved the way the wall split to show the stairway when the characters were looking out into it, that was very clever. The accents and facial expressions were very on point, they were extremely well done and put together. We only saw a recorded version of the show but I wouldn't be opposed to seeing a live performance. <br><a data-href="Terminology#Chekov's Gun" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/terminology.html#Chekov's Gun" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Terminology &gt; Chekov's Gun</a><a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/#fnref-1-afe5699806865589" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">↩︎</a>
]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/october-2025/the-shadow-of-a-gunman-(initial-viewing).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/October 2025/The Shadow of a Gunman (Initial Viewing).md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 01:28:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stage Plan & Monologue]]></title><description><![CDATA[(The aforementioned stage plan can be found in my Physical Portfolio, or alternatively <a data-href="here" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">here</a>)C1: “This idiot has no idea what’s coming to him. I’m gonna blow his stupid little head off. Why couldn’t he have just stuck to the plan, everything would’ve been fine, but noooo, he had to get greedy, well he knew what the boss said."
C1, in a kind of high and mighty mock voice: 'He said 'Go in and bring back the boy and the girl unharmed' and yet here lies the boy, dead on the floor. And it’s not like we can just get rid of him now. Oh what am I do to now."]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/stage-plan-&amp;-monologue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Stage Plan &amp; Monologue.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 20:05:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Into the Woods P2]]></title><description><![CDATA[Into The Woods by James Lopine, in my opinion is a fantastic show and needs to be watched/attended. The production that we attended in Gorey Little Theatre is no exception to that, the amazing team of set designers, actors, costume designers, musicians and make-up artists did a brilliant job at bringing this show to life. And it could even be seen by a blind man, that an incredible amount of love, care, time and effort went into this production.Now we only saw the dress rehearsal of act 1 on the night but it was brilliant nonetheless. During the show the team made excellent use of all sorts of techniques: The use of lighting was well done, they were still testing it while we were watching it because it was the dress rehearsal but they definitely got it spot on. Most might not have caught it but there were a couple of little soliloquies sprinkled in throughout the show. The costume design was spectacular especially for the witch, her entire face and identity was obscured till the very last moment at the end when she transforms. The set design I think was one of the best I've ever seen if not the best I've seen, creating an amazing atmosphere. The singing was brilliant as well, I have quite a fondness for musicals so that aspect of the show really spoke to me, so much that the main song with the whole cast saying "Into The Woods, dun dun Into the Woods..." has been stuck in my mind ever since. I would absolutely love to see more musicals in the future as per my aforementioned fondness of them, but I understand if this isn't possible. ]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/into-the-woods-p2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Into the Woods P2.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 20:05:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Into the Woods P1]]></title><description><![CDATA[On Monday the 15th of September 2025, we saw a dress rehearsal of the Musical Into the Woods.
The reflection for this show can be found in the <a data-href="Into the Woods P2" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/into-the-woods-p2.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Into the Woods P2</a> file, or below if the embedding feature works.Into The Woods by James Lopine, in my opinion is a fantastic show and needs to be watched/attended. The production that we attended in Gorey Little Theatre is no exception to that, the amazing team of set designers, actors, costume designers, musicians and make-up artists did a brilliant job at bringing this show to life. And it could even be seen by a blind man, that an incredible amount of love, care, time and effort went into this production.Now we only saw the dress rehearsal of act 1 on the night but it was brilliant nonetheless. During the show the team made excellent use of all sorts of techniques: The use of lighting was well done, they were still testing it while we were watching it because it was the dress rehearsal but they definitely got it spot on. Most might not have caught it but there were a couple of little soliloquies sprinkled in throughout the show. The costume design was spectacular especially for the witch, her entire face and identity was obscured till the very last moment at the end when she transforms. The set design I think was one of the best I've ever seen if not the best I've seen, creating an amazing atmosphere. The singing was brilliant as well, I have quite a fondness for musicals so that aspect of the show really spoke to me, so much that the main song with the whole cast saying "Into The Woods, dun dun Into the Woods..." has been stuck in my mind ever since. I would absolutely love to see more musicals in the future as per my aforementioned fondness of them, but I understand if this isn't possible. ]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/into-the-woods-p1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Into the Woods P1.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 20:05:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Improvisation on the 8th]]></title><description><![CDATA[Improvisation is engaging in an activity that is not preplanned or prepared. There is spontaneity and freedom in the approach, allowing the activity to develop naturally without constraints.I was able to be creative in my approach to my work in class, particularly in the bit of adding sentences of the internal monologue to our Still Scenes from the previous class.I learned that I know a lot more that I previously realised and that I am not as bad as I thought I was with coming up with dialogue.I can try to retain everything I’ve learned and pay closer attention to the show that we’ll be attending on <a data-href="Into the Woods P1" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/into-the-woods-p1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Into the Woods P1</a>, next week.]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/improvisation-on-the-8th.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Improvisation on the 8th.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 20:05:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Creative Groups]]></title><description><![CDATA[I think the most crucial part of what makes a creative group work well together, is the desire &amp; passion for the work. If no one is interested and passionate about working together and making a project come to life, they won’t be able to work well together. In addition to this I think it’s important for the members of the group to be of similar age/generation as this tends to have members being of the same culture and being able to connect easier. I also think in order for a creative project to be brought to life, the members need to have similar weight in the decision of what the work/project they’ll be doing will be.]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/creative-groups.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Creative Groups.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 20:05:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[September 2025]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website?query=tag:Month" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Month">#Month</a>This is the file in which all the events of September will be detailed, any of the dates that are highlighted and/or underlined can be clicked to go the file associated with that day.]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/september-2025.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/September 2025.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Calendar]]></title><description><![CDATA[Year 1<a data-href="September 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/september-2025/september-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">September 2025</a><br><a data-href="December 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">December 2025</a><br><a data-href="March 2026" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">March 2026</a><br><a data-href="October 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/october-2025/october-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">October 2025</a><br><a data-href="January 2026" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">January 2026</a><br><a data-href="April 2026" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">April 2026</a><br><a data-href="November 2025" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/november-2025/november-2025.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">November 2025</a><br><a data-href="February 2026" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">February 2026</a><br><a data-href="May 2026" href="https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">May 2026</a>]]></description><link>https://astralis0.github.io/drama-portfolio-website/calendar/calendar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/Calendar.canvas</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:49:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[ACT 1 Portfolio Prompt]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="acts/act-1/act-1-portfolio-prompt.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>acts/act-1/act-1-portfolio-prompt.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ACTs/ACT 1/ACT 1 Portfolio Prompt.jpg</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:42:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ACT 1 Script]]></title><link>calendar/october-2025/act-1-script.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/October 2025/ACT 1 Script.pdf</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:37:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[test]]></title><link>calendar/october-2025/test.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/October 2025/test.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 13:37:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Monday the 8th]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Day" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Day">#Day</a>Improvisation is engaging in an activity that is not preplanned or prepared. There is spontaneity and freedom in the approach, allowing the activity to develop naturally without constraints.I was able to be creative in my approach to my work in class, particularly in the bit of adding sentences of the internal monologue to our Still Scenes from the previous class.I learned that I know a lot more that I previously realised and that I am not as bad as I thought I was with coming up with dialogue.<br>I can try to retain everything I’ve learned and pay closer attention to the show that we’ll be attending on <a data-href="Monday the 15th" href="calendar/september-2025/monday-the-15th.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Monday the 15th</a>, next week.]]></description><link>calendar/september-2025/monday-the-8th.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Monday the 8th.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 22:01:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Monday the 15th]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Day" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Day">#Day</a> On Monday the 15th of September 2025, we saw a dress rehearsal of the Musical Into the Woods.<br>
The reflection for this show can be found in the <a data-href="Wednesday the 17th" href="calendar/september-2025/wednesday-the-17th.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wednesday the 17th</a> file, or below if the embedding feature works.Into The Woods by James Lopine, in my opinion is a fantastic show and needs to be watched/attended. The production that we attended in Gorey Little Theatre is no exception to that, the amazing team of set designers, actors, costume designers, musicians and make-up artists did a brilliant job at bringing this show to life. And it could even be seen by a blind man, that an incredible amount of love, care, time and effort went into this production.Now we only saw the dress rehearsal of act 1]]></description><link>calendar/september-2025/monday-the-15th.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Monday the 15th.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 22:01:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wednesday the 17th]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Day" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Day">#Day</a> Into The Woods by James Lopine, in my opinion is a fantastic show and needs to be watched/attended. The production that we attended in Gorey Little Theatre is no exception to that, the amazing team of set designers, actors, costume designers, musicians and make-up artists did a brilliant job at bringing this show to life. And it could even be seen by a blind man, that an incredible amount of love, care, time and effort went into this production.Now we only saw the dress rehearsal of act 1]]></description><link>calendar/september-2025/wednesday-the-17th.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Wednesday the 17th.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:06:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wednesday the 3rd]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Day" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Day">#Day</a>I think the most crucial part of what makes a creative group work well together, is the desire &amp; passion for the work. If no one is interested and passionate about working together and making a project come to life, they won’t be able to work well together. In addition to this I think it’s important for the members of the group to be of similar age/generation as this tends to have members being of the same culture and being able to connect easier. I also think in order for a creative project to be brought to life, the members need to have similar weight in the decision of what the work/project they’ll be doing will be.]]></description><link>calendar/september-2025/wednesday-the-3rd.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Wednesday the 3rd.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:06:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thursday the 11th]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Day" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Day">#Day</a> <br>(The aforementioned stage plan can be found in my Physical Portfolio, or alternatively <a data-href="here" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">here</a>)C1: “This idiot has no idea what’s coming to him. I’m gonna blow his stupid little head off. Why couldn’t he have just stuck to the plan, everything would’ve been fine, but noooo, he had to get greedy, well he knew what the boss said."
C1, in a kind of high and mighty mock voice: 'He said 'Go in and bring back the boy and the girl unharmed' and yet here lies the boy, dead on the floor. And it’s not like we can just get rid of him now. Oh what am I do to now."]]></description><link>calendar/september-2025/thursday-the-11th.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Calendar/September 2025/Thursday the 11th.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:06:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[and another one]]></title><description><![CDATA[because I messed with it]]></description><link>and-another-one.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">and another one.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:38:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[test]]></title><description><![CDATA[so what happens if I make a new file then?]]></description><link>test.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">test.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:19:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>